Guide to the William T. Gannaway papers, 1853-1906
Duke University. University Archives
William T. Gannaway papers 1853-1906
Duke University. University Archives
Gannaway, William T.
2.4 linear feet Extent: 40 Items
William Gannaway was a Professor of Latin and History at Trinity College in Randolph County from 1857 until his retirement in 1892. The collection includes account books and grade books as well as a small amount of correspondence and notes. The material ranges in date from 1853-1906.
RL.01584
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
Unknown.
Biographical Note
William Trigg Gannaway was born in Wythe County, Virginia in 1826. He graduated from Emory and Henry College in Bristol, Tennessee in 1847. In the autumn of that year, he opened a high school at Floyd Court House, Virginia. He conducted this school for a few years when he was elected head of a high school at Germanton, North Carolina. He ran this school until he was appointed Professor of Latin and History at Trinity College in Randolph County, North Carolina in 1857. In the absence of Braxton Craven, Gannaway served as President of the college from 1863-1865. He remained at Trinity College until it moved to Durham in 1892, when he retired from teaching. After retiring, he kept his home and farm in Randolph County. He died in 1911.
Collection Overview
The collection largely includes grade books and account books. These consist of personal account books (Gannaway, like many other teachers, was also a working farmer) and college account books. They have not been separated. The is a report to the Trustees from 1864 as well as miscellaneous memoranda, receipts, financial records and notes, and a small amount of correspondence, including a letter from E. F. Finch in 1888 that concerns the financial affairs of Charles Heitman and their effects on Trinity College. The material ranges in date from 1853-1906.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Gannaway, William T.; Trinity College (Randolph County, N.C.)--History.; Trinity College (Randolph County, N.C.)--Faculty.; Account books.
Related Material
Trinity College (Randolph County, N.C.) collection, 1836-1990
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 2 Boxes
  - Account Book, 1875-1877 (Oversize 1)
  - Account Book, 1872
  - Expense Book, 1878
  - Account Book, 1878-1885
  - Day Book, 1853-1877
  - Grade Book, 1886-1887
  - Account Book, 1872
  - Grade Book, 1873
  - Grade Book, 1869
  - Grade Book, undated
  - Grade Book, 1873
  - Account Book, 1861-1865
  - Account Book, 1870-1871
  - Expense Account, Trinity College (Randolph Co.), 1882-1887 (Oversize 2)
  - Receipt Book, 1882-1883
  - Account Book, 1883-1884
  - Account Book, 1886-1906
  - Account Book, 1888-1891
  - Account Book, 1892-1899
  - Account Book pages, 1900-1902 (folder)
  - Papers, including receipts and correspondence (folder)